Makes an authenticated HTTP request to the GitHub API and prints the response.

The endpoint argument should either be a path of a GitHub API v3 endpoint, or
"graphql" to access the GitHub API v4.

Placeholder values "{owner}", "{repo}", and "{branch}" in the endpoint
argument will get replaced with values from the repository of the current
directory or the repository specified in the GH_REPO environment variable.
Note that in some shells, for example PowerShell, you may need to enclose
any value that contains "{...}" in quotes to prevent the shell from
applying special meaning to curly braces.

The default HTTP request method is "GET" normally and "POST" if any parameters
were added. Override the method with `--method`.

Pass one or more `-f/--raw-field` values in "key=value" format to add static string
parameters to the request payload. To add non-string or placeholder-determined values, see
`--field` below. Note that adding request parameters will automatically switch the
request method to POST. To send the parameters as a GET query string instead, use
`--method GET`.

The `-F/--field` flag has magic type conversion based on the format of the value:

- literal values "true", "false", "null", and integer numbers get converted to
  appropriate JSON types;
- placeholder values "{owner}", "{repo}", and "{branch}" get populated with values
  from the repository of the current directory;
- if the value starts with "@", the rest of the value is interpreted as a
  filename to read the value from. Pass "-" to read from standard input.

For GraphQL requests, all fields other than "query" and "operationName" are
interpreted as GraphQL variables.

To pass nested parameters in the request payload, use "key[subkey]=value" syntax when
declaring fields. To pass nested values as arrays, declare multiple fields with the
syntax "key[]=value1", "key[]=value2". To pass an empty array, use "key[]" without a
value.

To pass pre-constructed JSON or payloads in other formats, a request body may be read
from file specified by `--input`. Use "-" to read from standard input. When passing the
request body this way, any parameters specified via field flags are added to the query
string of the endpoint URL.

In `--paginate` mode, all pages of results will sequentially be requested until
there are no more pages of results. For GraphQL requests, this requires that the
original query accepts an `$endCursor: String` variable and that it fetches the
`pageInfo{ hasNextPage, endCursor }` set of fields from a collection.

For more information about output formatting flags, see `gh help formatting`.

USAGE
  gh api <endpoint> [flags]

FLAGS
      --cache duration        Cache the response, e.g. "3600s", "60m", "1h"
  -F, --field key=value       Add a typed parameter in key=value format
  -H, --header key:value      Add a HTTP request header in key:value format
      --hostname string       The GitHub hostname for the request (default "github.com")
  -i, --include               Include HTTP response status line and headers in the output
      --input file            The file to use as body for the HTTP request (use "-" to read from standard input)
  -q, --jq string             Query to select values from the response using jq syntax
  -X, --method string         The HTTP method for the request (default "GET")
      --paginate              Make additional HTTP requests to fetch all pages of results
  -p, --preview names         GitHub API preview names to request (without the "-preview" suffix)
  -f, --raw-field key=value   Add a string parameter in key=value format
      --silent                Do not print the response body
  -t, --template string       Format JSON output using a Go template; see "gh help formatting"
      --verbose               Include full HTTP request and response in the output

INHERITED FLAGS
  --help   Show help for command

EXAMPLES
  # list releases in the current repository
  $ gh api repos/{owner}/{repo}/releases
  
  # post an issue comment
  $ gh api repos/{owner}/{repo}/issues/123/comments -f body='Hi from CLI'
  
  # post nested parameter read from a file
  $ gh api gists -F 'files[myfile.txt][content]=@myfile.txt'
  
  # add parameters to a GET request
  $ gh api -X GET search/issues -f q='repo:cli/cli is:open remote'
  
  # set a custom HTTP header
  $ gh api -H 'Accept: application/vnd.github.v3.raw+json' ...
  
  # opt into GitHub API previews
  $ gh api --preview baptiste,nebula ...
  
  # print only specific fields from the response
  $ gh api repos/{owner}/{repo}/issues --jq '.[].title'
  
  # use a template for the output
  $ gh api repos/{owner}/{repo}/issues --template \
    '{{range .}}{{.title}} ({{.labels | pluck "name" | join ", " | color "yellow"}}){{"\n"}}{{end}}'
  
  # list releases with GraphQL
  $ gh api graphql -F owner='{owner}' -F name='{repo}' -f query='
    query($name: String!, $owner: String!) {
      repository(owner: $owner, name: $name) {
        releases(last: 3) {
          nodes { tagName }
        }
      }
    }
  '
  
  # list all repositories for a user
  $ gh api graphql --paginate -f query='
    query($endCursor: String) {
      viewer {
        repositories(first: 100, after: $endCursor) {
          nodes { nameWithOwner }
          pageInfo {
            hasNextPage
            endCursor
          }
        }
      }
    }
  '

ENVIRONMENT VARIABLES
  GH_TOKEN, GITHUB_TOKEN (in order of precedence): an authentication token for
  github.com API requests.
  
  GH_ENTERPRISE_TOKEN, GITHUB_ENTERPRISE_TOKEN (in order of precedence): an
  authentication token for API requests to GitHub Enterprise.
  
  GH_HOST: make the request to a GitHub host other than github.com.

LEARN MORE
  Use 'gh <command> <subcommand> --help' for more information about a command.
  Read the manual at https://cli.github.com/manual

